# **MATTEO CRISTIANO**

#### **PERSONAL DATA**

Residence: Via San Matteo 82G, 00015 Monterotondo (RM)

Mobile phone: +39 349 2913958 E-mail: slb6113@gmail.com

GitHub profile: <a href="https://github.com/Sennar19">https://github.com/Sennar19</a>
GitLab profile: <a href="https://gitlab.com/slb6113">https://gitlab.com/slb6113</a>
Twitter profile: <a href="https://twitter.com/slb6113">https://twitter.com/slb6113</a>

LinkedIn profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matteo-cristiano-20788a104

Driving license: B, A3 Nationality: Italian

Place and date of birth: Ferrara (Fe), September 10<sup>th</sup> 1992



## **EDUCATION**

2023 HashiCorp Cloud Engineer Certifications: Terraform Associate 003, released by HashiCorp

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Google IT Support Professional Certificate, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the IT Security: Defense against the digital darks, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Introduction to Docker, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Kubernetes: Basic Architecture and First Deployment, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Terraform for absolute beginners, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Introduction to Ansible: The Fundamentals, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Operating Systems and You: Becoming a Power User, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Technical Support Fundamentals, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Introduction to TCP/IP, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Architecting on AWS, released by Amazon Web Services (AWS)

2020 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Advanced Networking Specialty (LA) course, released by Linux Academy

2020 Certificate of Completion of the Ansible Quick Start course, released by Linux Academy

2020 Certificate of Completion of the Architecting on AWS course, released by Amazon Web Services (AWS)

2020 Certificate of Completion of the How to Get a Linux Job course, released by Linux Academy

2020 Certificate of Completion of the Introduction to Ansible (LA) course, released by Linux Academy

2020 Certificate of Completion of the **Certificate of Attendance - AWS Innovative Online Conference - AI/ML Edition** course, released by *Amazon Web Services (AWS)* 

2020 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Certified Machine Learning - Speciality course, released by Linux Academy

2020 Certificate of Completion of the **Certificate of Completion - Top 5 Machine Learning Libraries in Python** course, released by *Udemy* 

2019 Certificate of Completion of the **Certificate of Completion - Introduction to Python Programming** course, released by *Udemy* 

2019 Certificate of Completion of the **Leading like a Futurist** course, released by *LinkedIn* 

2019 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate Level course, released by Linux Academy

2019 Certificate of Completion of the **Certificate of Attendance - AWS Innovative Online Conference - Machine Learning and AI Edition** course, released by *Amazon Web Services (AWS)* 

2019 Certificate of Completion of the Learn AWS by Doing course, released by Linux Academy

2019 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Concepts course, released by Linux Academy

2019 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Essentials course, released by Linux Academy

2019 Certificate of Completion of the **AWS Security Essentials** course, released by *Linux Academy* 

2019 Certificate of Completion of the **Linux Operating System Fundamentals** course, released by *Linux Academy* 

2015-2018 **Master's degree** in **Astronomy and Astrophysics**, from "*La Sapienza*" University of Rome, with vote **109/110**, with thesis "*Violent relaxation of self gravitating systems*" (supervisor: Prof. Roberto Capuzzo Dolcetta), and the following exams:

- Theoretical Astrophysics [eng] (6 U.C.): 30/30
- Astrophysical Processes and Plasmas (6 U.C.): 25/30
- Stellar Systems Dynamics (6 U.C.): 30 e lode/30
- General Relativity (6 U.C.): 30/30
- Intensive Computing [eng] (6 U.C.): 30/30
- Physical Cosmology [eng] (6 U.C.): 30 e lode/30

- Astrophysics Laboratory (12 U.C.): 30/30
- Advanced Computing Laboratory (6 U.C.): 30/30
- Self-gravitating Systems (6 U.C.): 30 e lode/30
- Stellar Astrophysics (6 U.C.): 27/30
- University Tuition (3 U.C.): eligible
- Extragalactic Astrophysics (6 U.C.): 26/30
- Superior Physics (6 U.C.): 24/30

Weighted Average: 28.62/30 Arithmetic Average: 28.50/30

2018 Certificate of Completion of the **Learning Python** course, released by *LinkedIn* 

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Parallel I/O and management of large scientific data** course, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *Cineca* offices in Rome

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Introduction to Parallel Computing with MPI and Open MP** course, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *Cineca* offices in Rome

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Debugging and Optimization of Scientific Applications** course, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *Cineca* offices in Rome

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Introduction to Marconi KNL Cluster, for users and developers** workshop, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *CNR* offices in Rome

2011-2015 Bachelor's degree in Physics and Astrophysics, from "La Sapienza" University of Rome, with vote 106/110, with thesis "Regolarizzazione del Problema Gravitazionale Classico dei due e tre Corpi" (supervisor: Prof. Roberto Capuzzo Dolcetta) and the following exams:

- Calculus Laboratory (6 U.C.): 27/30
- Geometry (9 U.C.): 21/30
- Calculus I (9 U.C.): 29/30
- Mechanics Laboratory (12 U.C.): 30 e lode/30
- Mechanics (12 U.C.): 28/30
- Thermodynamics and Laboratory (9 U.C.): 23/30
- Electromagnetism and Circuits Laboratory (6 U.C.): 26/30
- Calculus II (9 U.C.): 28/30
- Celestial Mechanics (6 U.C.): 29/30
- Astronomy (9 U.C.): 30 e lode/30
- Chemistry (6 U.C.): 29/30
- Astrophysics (9 U.C.): 28/30
- Numerical Methods for Astronomy (6 U.C.): 28/30
- English Language (2 U.C.): eligible
- Optics and Laboratory (9 U.C.): 26/30
- English Language (3 U.C.): eligible
- Mathematical Methods for Physics (6 U.C.): 25/30
- Electromagnetism (12 U.C.): 29/30
- Statistical Mechanics (6 U.C.): 26/30
- Nuclear and Subnuclear Physics I (6 U.C.): 21/30
- Quantum Mechanics (9 U.C.): 20/30
- Astrophysics Laboratory (12 U.C.): 30 e lode/30
- Matter Structure (6 U.C.): 25/30

Weighted Average: 26.81/30 Arithmetic Average: 26.57/30

2006-2011 **Scientific Graduation** (P.N.I. course), at the Scientific Public High School "A. Roiti" in Ferrara (Fe), with vote **92/100** 2011 Certificate of attendance to **Excellence course for High Schools**, at the "Department of Physics" at the "University of Ferrara" (Fe), and winner of the scholarship related to a visit to the **CERN** 

2011 Certificate of attendance to **Astrophysics Laboratory**, at the "Department of Physics" at the "University of Ferrara" (Fe), organized during the **Progetto Lauree Scientifiche** 

2011 ECDL Core certificate (Full certificate)

2010 Certificate of attendance to **Chemistry summer stage**, at the "Department of Physics" at the "University of Ferrara" (Fe), organized during the **Progetto Lauree Scientifiche** 

2010 Certificate of attendance to **Chemistry Laboratory experimental course**, at the "Department of Chemistry" at the "University of Ferrara" (Fe), organized during the **Progetto Lauree Scientifiche**, with the acquisition of 1 U.C. (F type) with vote 30/30

2009 Certificate of attendance to **Summer-study-holidays** at the **Magister Academy** in Malta, with certificate of attendance to the **Upper Intermediate** (**CEF B2** level) level English language course

2008 Certificate of attendance to **Summer-study-holidays** at the **Bradfield College**, with certificate of attendance to the **Intermediate (CEF B1** level) level English language course

2007 Certificate of passing the Trinity College 4° degree exam (CEF A2.2 level and NQF Entry Level)

2007 Certificate of attendance to **Summer-study-holidays** at the **Strathallan School**, with certificate of attendance to the **Intermediate (CEF B1** level) level English language course

# **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Linux O.S., Microsoft Windows O.S., Python, Pascal, C/C++, Java, Javascript, Fortran, MPI, OpenMP, HDF, CUDA, HTML, JSP, CSS, Gnuplot, Bash Shell Scripting, SQL, MySQL, Angular, AngularJS, LaTeX, Matlab, Scilab, Origin, Microsoft Visual Studio, Office, Internet Explorer, Microsoft Edge, Outlook Express, Mozilla, Firefox, Google Chrome, OpenOffice, LibreOffice, AWS, SonarQube, Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikit, Laravel, Yii, PHP, Git, WordPress, Packer, Ansible, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, RDS, Aurora, API Gateway, Jenkins, Cloud, Terraform, Azure DevOps, Powershell Scripting, Octopus, MS SQL, GSuite, Office 365, Docker, Docker Compose, Kubernetes, ArgoCD, EKS, RedGate, Network, Security, Landing Zone, Documentation, Confluence, Azure, Cloud

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Italian: native language (C2)

French: elementary (A1), both written and spoken English: professional (B2), both written and spoken

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

June 2023 - present

#### Cloud Architecture & Operations Expert at Lottomatica, Rome:

I'm working as Cloud Architect, for the Lottomatica Cloud team: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on Azure cloud (using Terraform), from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Azure DevOps), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I manage creation and integration between different systems (Azure DevOps, Kubernetes, Graphana, DataBricks, ..), and Kubernetes cluster (on-prem, and AKS). I'm also involved in the creation of infrastructure, and CI\CD processes of a Data Platform project, managing the MLOps workflow.

- CI/CD
- Azure DevOps
- Terraform
- Network/Security (VNet, NSGs, Route Tables, Peering, VPN S2S, ..)
- Azure
- Ubuntu, Windows
- Git
- Bash/Python/Powershell scripting
- Docker/Docker Compose
- Kubernetes, AKS
- Helm
- DataBricks
- Data Factory
- Storage Account
- Application Gateway
- WAF
- Confluence
- Jira

### April 2022 - June 2023

## International Platform Operations Expert at Lottomatica, Rome:

I'm working as Cloud Engineer, for the Lottomatica Cloud team, in an international project: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS cloud (using Terraform), from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Azure DevOps), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes.

I manage creation and integration between different systems (Azure DevOps, ArgoCD, Kubernetes, Graphana, SonarQube, ...), servers life cycle (via Ansible processes), and Kubernetes cluster (on-prem, and EKS). About AWS, I had the possibility to work with Local Zones, and Outposts.

- Ansible
- CloudWatch/Events/Dashboard
- CI/CD
- Azure DevOps
- Terraform
- SonarQube
- Network/Security (VPC, NACLs, SGs, Route Tables, Transit Gateway, VPN, ..)

- AWS
- CentOS, Ubuntu, Windows, RedHat
- Git
- Bash/Python/Powershell scripting
- Docker/Docker Compose
- Kubernetes, EKS
- ArgoCD
- Confluence

# April 2020 - April 2022

# System Administrator & Cloud Engineer at ConTe.it - Admiral Group, Rome:

I'm working as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of Cl/CD processes. Recently, I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. I manage the integration between different systems (Graphana, SonarQube, Jenkins, ..), and the servers life cycle via Packer/Ansible processes.

- Packer
- Ansible
- CodePipeline/CodeBuild
- RDS/Aurora/MySQL/SQL Server
- API Gateway/Lambda Functions
- CloudWatch/Events/Dashboard
- AWS Transfer Family/SFTP
- CI/CD
- Jenkins
- SonarQube
- WordPress Administration
- Network/Security (VPC, NACLs, SGs, Route Tables, ..)
- AWS
- CentOS, RedHat
- Git/CodeCommit
- Bash/Python scripting

# June 2018 - March 2020

# <u>Software Developer Junior at ConTe.it - Admiral Group, Rome:</u>

I'm a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework (TDD & BDD methodology, code versioning using Git and CodeCommit); every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process.

- PHP
- SonarQube
- SQL, MySQL
- Unit/E2E test
- Bash shell scripting
- CodePipeline/CodeBuild
- ETL
- DataPipeline
- RDS/Aurora
- Git/CodeCommit
- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- Laravel
- AWS

2015 - 2021

2012

Private lessons in mathemathics, physics, and natural science (primary school, secondary school, high school, university level)

Collaborative work as vigilant of the <u>Calculus Laboratory</u>, at the "*La Sapienza*" University of Rome

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm 31 years old, I'm graduate in "Astronomy and Astrophysic" - at the "La Sapienza" University of Rome - and I'm specialized on dynamics of dense stellar systems and exoplanets systems. I have been for about 2 years a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework; every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and

managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process. I worked as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in this role, I managed the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. At the moment, I'm working as Cloud Architecture & Operations Expert, at Lottomatica, managing VMs, kubernetes clusters, and CI\CD processes built on AWS and Azure clouds. I am also interested in Machine Learning and Data Science topics/processes. I'm an extrovert guy, I like to work in team (more brains are better than one!), and I'm always ready to test and improve my own skills, overcoming my limits.

Ctrl - Create the roaring impossible

Monterotondo (RM), 01/02/2024

Matteo Cristiano